You can talk to me, we can laugh and smile
Eikaiwa Time Trial
Let's get started with Day 12 for the month of September.
Hi everyone, I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
This time, we're going to talk about the pattern of clothes, such as check patterns, stripes, and water balloons.
Actually, check patterns are just check.
ではなかなか通じません
相手に伝わりやすい表現を一緒に練習して
文の形で表現できるようになりましょう
And one more thing today
Our radio show will be in
Almost all English
今日のレッスンはほぼ
All Englishで進みます
Don't worry, you can do it
Okay, it's time for your first try
S-P-R
Training
I'll say something in Japanese, and you express it in English.
Before we do the first sentence, let's check this vocabulary word.
チェックの柄
How do you say that in English?
The answer is plaid.
P-L-A-I-D, plaid.
Now, use plaid to make this sentence.
チェックをよく着ますか?
Say it in English.
Go ahead.
Okay, here's the next one.
そのチェックのマフラーはすごくいいですね。
チェックはほとんどきません。
Start with, I almost never...
Go ahead.
Before we go on to the next sentence, let's check this vocabulary word.
How do you say STRIPE in English?
For CLOSE, it's in the plural.
FUKUSUKE, STRIPES.
OKAY.
Use the word STRIPES to say this.
私にはストライプは似合いますか?
私はストライプだと痩せて見えるんです。
I look...
Go ahead.
And before we go to the next one,
Let's check out this phrase about clothes.
ストライプのシャツ
How do you say that in English?
The answer is striped shirt.
You could say a shirt with stripes too.
But let's use striped shirt to say this.
ストライプのシャツとジーンズを着るのが好きです。
And here's the next one.
このカフェにはストライプのシャツを着た人が3人もいます。
OK, let's check out one more pattern for clothes before we go to the next sentence.
How do you say みずたま、みずたまもよう in English?
In English, Mizutama is polka dots.
All right, use polka dots to say this.
Watashi ni wa Mizutama wa niyaimasen.
Sono Mizutama no One Piece wa sugoku kawaii desu ne.
Okay, time's up. How did you do? Did you try to say each one?
Now, Jenny and I will show you the sample answers and give you some advice.
So listen closely.
Do you wear plaid often?
I love that plaid scarf.
チェックはほとんど着ません。
I almost never wear plaid.
This is a useful phrase.
ほとんど何々しません。
Almost neverを使って
I almost never何々。
OK, here's the next one.
スコットランド旅行のために
このチェックのベストを買いました。
I got this plaid vest
for my trip to Scotland.
スコットランド旅行は
私にはストライプは似合いますか?
私はストライプだと痩せて見えるんです
痩せてる体型についてスキニーを使ってもいいんですが
スレンダーの方がエレガントな言葉です
ストライプのシャツとジーンズを着るのが好きです。
このカフェにはストライプのシャツを着た人が3人もいます。
私には水玉は似合いません。
Polka dots don't look good on me.
And of course, you can also say, I don't look good in polka dots.
その水玉のワンピースはすごくかわいいですね。
That polka dot dress is adorable.
すごくかわいい。
Adorable.
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
Alright, now it's your turn to try them one more time.
Do your best.
Okay, let's go.
Do you often wear plaid?
Do you wear plaid often?
The plaid muffler is really good, isn't it?
I love that plaid scarf.
チェックはほとんど着ません。
I almost never wear plaid.
スコットランド旅行のためにこのチェックのベストを買いました。
I got this plaid vest for my trip to Scotland.
私にはストライプは似合いますか?
Do I look good in stripes?
私はストライプだと痩せて見えるんです。
I look slender in stripes.
ストライプのシャツとジーンズを着るのが好きです。
I like to wear a striped shirt and jeans.
このカフェにはストライプのシャツを着た人が3人もいます。
There are three people wearing striped shirts in this cafe.
私には水玉は似合いません。
Polka-dots don't look good on me.
その水玉のワンピースはすごくかわいいですね。
That polka-dot dress is adorable.
Okay, time's up.
Well, how did you do?
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on A-Kaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.